ASIF AHMED NELOY | Curriculum Vitae

asif.neloy@northsouth.edu, aneloy@ieee.org https://aaneloy.netlify.com/ +88 018 6082 6446

Updated: January 2nd, 2020

CAREER INTEREST

Seeking a position in Algorithms, Data Structure, Data Science, Data Analysis and Robotics where extensive experience will be further developed and utilized. Skilled in machine learning, statistics, problem-solving, business analysis, algorithms, data visualization, and creative thinking. Commitment to providing support and essential information about trends to companies in a variety of industries.

RESEARCH INTEREST

My primary field of research interest is Artificial Intelligence (AI). Within AI, I am interested in problems related to probabilistic modeling, machine learning, data mining, and interdisciplinary applications of computer vision. My research revolves around elegant modeling of problems of practical interest, understanding the fundamental principles of statistical machine learning, designing scalable algorithms with guarantees, and analyzing their computational and information-theoretic properties rigorously. Moreover, with the help of modeling and scheme of AI, I have also a substantial overview in the field of Robotics, more precisely – Design Analysis, Path Finding, Robot Vision, Object Tracking and application of Probabilistic Models to the segmentation problem.

EDUCATION

North South University (NSU), Bashundhara, Dhaka 1229, Bangladesh

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and Engineering January 2015 - December 2018

CGPA – 3.30/4.00 (87% - 89% Marks)

Upper Quartile CGPA – 3.65/4.00 (90% - 92% Marks)

Specialized Trail – Artificial Intelligence

Bachelor Thesis – Early Health Prediction System for ICU Patient using

Machine Learning and Cloud Computing.

Ananda Mohan College, Mymensingh Sadar, Mymensingh, Bangladesh

Higher Secondary School Certificate (HSC)

July 2012 - July 2014

Group - Science GPA: 5.00/5.00

Secondary School Certificate(SSC)

March 2012

Group - Science GPA: 5.00/5.00

EXPERIENCE

Advanced Chemical Industries (ACI Ltd.), Dhaka, Bangladesh

• Information Analyst

January 2020 - Present

- ❖ Interpret and translate data into valuable information effective for analysis purposes.
- ❖ Analyze client's requirements to provide suggestions in order to deliver products that are aligned with the ultimate business requirement.
- Oversee implementation of a new system, support users in adapting to the system by ensuring proper training and guidelines.

North South University (NSU), Dhaka 1229, Bangladesh

• Laboratory Officer

May 2019 - Present

Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering (ECE)

- ❖ Responsible for conducting the lab classes of the enrolled students. Lab Coursework includes implementing algorithms and theoretical concepts with respective programming languages as deemed necessary by the course curriculum. Also responsible for grading and marking the students in their lab classes.
- Undergraduate Teaching Assistant (UGA)
 Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering (ECE)

 January 2019 May 2019
 - ❖ Facilitate a discussion section or tutorial; hold weekly office hours; grade homework, programming assignments, exams, or projects; keep records; distribute and copy reading materials; prepare answer keys or supplementary notes, and act as the course web-master
 - ❖ Assisting faculty with recordkeeping, such as tracking attendance and calculating grades.

Youthpreneur Network, Dhaka 1217, Bangladesh

Head of Robotics and Data Science.

August 2017 — January 2019

❖ Youthpreneur Network Academy is a concern program of Desire Glance Group. The aim of this academy is to creative tech enthusiast people from the very early stage of school and college and Endorse knowledge about different sectors of the tech world.

- ❖ Under my supervision, several projects launched, successfully developing and overseeing project budgets, schedules, staffing requirements, and SDLC tasks to comprehensively manage all facets of implementation and execution throughout my tenure as an HoD with GoTime Client Services.
- ❖ Prepared Five-year Strategic Plan and Business plan for "National Space Carnival" and "Bangladesh General Knowledge Olympiad"
- ❖ I have also worked as a mentor and Trainer of the Robotics and data analysis section of Desire Glance Group.

NSU ACM Student Chapter, Dhaka, Bangladesh

• Founding Secretary

January 2017 — November 2017

• Vice Chair

November 2017 — December 2018

- ❖ NSU ACM Student Chapter is the first chartered Student Chapter in Bangladesh, the world's largest educational and scientific computing society.
- ❖ As a Secretary and Vice-Chair, I have managed all the administrative workflows and workshop during the fiscal year 2017-2018. I also received Recognition of Service Award from ACM NY HQ.
- ❖ Certified Trainer of NSU ACM Student Chapter from February 2017 to 2019.
- ❖ Undertook workshops on Machine Learning, Basic Robotics, PCB Design and Robot Operating System (ROS).

ACADEMIC HONORS AND AWARDS

- Certified Mentor of Robotics and Machine learning.
- 1st Runner Up for the final year Capstone Project, Capstone Innovation Challenge, Season 6, 2018.
- Runner up IEEE day Hackathon 2017.
- Junior Board Scholarship Class 8.

LANGUAGES/PLATFORMS

Proficient C, C++, Python, Java.

Familiar with PHP, JS, SQL, Julia, HTML, CSS, ROS.

Data Science Tools Tableau, SPSS, MATLAB, Apache Spark. Anaconda

Platforms IBM Cloud, IBM Watson Studio, Jupyter, PyCharm, GIT,

UNIX Systems, Docker, Arduino.

WORKSHOP/SEMINAR CONDUCTED

- Workshop on Robotics Robo101, NSU ACM Student Chapter. Spring 2017, Fall 2017, Summer 2018.
- Workshop on Intro to Machine Learning, NSU ACM Student Chapter. Fall 2018.
- Hour of Code, Association for Computing Machinery (ACM), December 9, 2018.

PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES

IEEE Student Member: 94560705 ACM Student Member: 9654439

TEACHING

North South University (NSU), Dhaka 1229, Bangladesh	
CSE231L Digital Logic design	Summer 2019
CSE332L Computer Organization and Architecture	Summer 2019
CSE482L Internet and Web Technology	Summer 2019
CSE115L Programming Language I	Fall 2019
CSE331L Microprocessor Interfacing & Embedded System	Spring 2019, Fall 2019

RESEARCH FACILITY

Founder and Principal Investigator of TF-ROS Lab

Funding

BDT 500000 by Desire Glance Group for the fiscal year 2018-2019.

Members

6 undergraduate students of North South University.

LANGUAGE PROFICIENCY

IELTS 7.5 (W, R - 7.00, L, S - 8.00)

SERVICES

Guest Reviewer – 2019 The Fourth International Conference on Economic and Business Management (FEBM2019). China October 19-21, 2019.

BOOKS

Author of a book titled — "এসো রোবট বানাই- Let's make Robots", Publisher - Pinnacle Media, Publishing Year — November 2017. ISBN 978-984-34-3061-8.

PUBLICATIONS (Published/Submitted)

JOURNALS

1. **Asif Ahmed Neloy**, Aziz, Arman, Mohammad Samiul Islam, Tamanna Motahar (2018). **Automated Mobile Robot with RFID Scanner and Self Obstacle Avoiding System.** International Journal of Pure and Applied Mathematics, 118(18), 3139-3150.

BOOK CHAPTERS

- 1. Asif Ahmed Neloy, Muhammad Shafayat Oshman, Zunayeed Bin Zahir. Content-Based Health Recommender System for ICU Patient. Published in: Chamchong R., Wong K. (eds) Multi-disciplinary Trends in Artificial Intelligence. MIWAI 2019. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, vol 11909. Springer, Cham
- 2. Asif Ahmed Neloy, Rafia Alif Bindu, Sazid Alam, Ridwanul Haque, Md. Saif Ahammod Khan and Nasim Mahmud Mishu (2019). Alpha-N: Shortest Path Finder Automated Delivery Robot with Real-Time Object Detection and Avoiding System. Accepted for publication 12th Asian Conference on Intelligent Information and Database Systems (ACIIDS 2020).

CONFERENCE PAPERS

- 1. Asif Ahmed Neloy, H M Sadman Haque, Md. Mahmud Ul Islam (2019, February). Ensemble Learning Based Rental Apartment Price Prediction Model by Categorical Features Factoring. In Proceedings of the 2019 11th International Conference on Machine Learning and Computing (pp. 350-356). ACM.
- 2. Rafia Alif Bindu, Sazid Alam, Asif Ahmed Neloy (2019, March). A Cost-Efficient Multipurpose Service Robot using Raspberry Pi and 6 DOF Robotic Arm. In Proceedings of the 2019 2nd International Conference on Service Robotics Technologies (pp. 16-22). ACM.

- 3. Asif Ahmed Neloy, Sazid Alam, Rafia Alif Bindu, Nusrat Jahan Moni, "Machine Learning based Health Prediction System using IBM Cloud as PaaS," 2019 3rd International Conference on Trends in Electronics and Informatics (ICOEI), Tirunelveli, India, 2019, pp. 444-450.doi: 10.1109/ICOEI.2019.8862754
- 4. Rafia Alif Bindu, Asif Ahmed Neloy, Sazid Alam, Nusrat Jahan Moni, Dr. Shahnewaz Siddique (2019, August). Sigma-3: Integration and Analysis of a 6 DOF Robotic Arm Configuration in a Rescue Robot. Accepted for publication: 2019 4th International Conference on Robotics and Automation Engineering (ICRAE 2019).

ADDITIONAL RESOURCES

Google Scholar

http://bit.ly/2Uab0wq

Github

http://bit.ly/2Zs1A0t

URI Online Judge

http://bit.ly/2MG0mwH

Research Gate

http://bit.ly/2qrgpVc

PERSONAL

Citizenship	Bangladeshi
Marital Status	Unmarried
Love to	Walk/Run/Playing Games, read books, Cook for others (occasionally), Travel

I hereby declare that the above-mentioned information is correct to the best of my knowledge and belief.

ASIF AHMED NELOY 02.01.2020

REFERENCES

- 1. Md. Shazzad Hosain, Ph.D.
 Professor(Co-Supervisor)
 Department of Electrical &
 Computer Engineering, North
 South University.
 shazzad.hosain@northsouth.edu
 +880255668200, Ext 1534
- 3. Zunayeed Bin Zahir

 Lecturer (Supervisor)

 Department of Electrical &

 Computer Engineering, North

 South University.

 zunayeed.zahir01@northsouth.edu
 +880255668200 Ext 6191.
- 2. Mirza Mohammad Lutfe Elahi Senior Lecturer
 Department of Electrical & Computer Engineering, North South University.
 lutfe.elahi@northsouth.edu
 +8802-55668200, Ext 1513